# Revaz Zakalashvili

Email: revaz.zakalashvili@gmail.com

### **Summary**

Software engineer, with the experience of building pixel perfect and speed optimized applications. For the past 3 years I mainly was working on React and Typescript. Currently I'm diving deeper in type systems and advanced animations.

# **Experience**

### Full-stack Software Engineer @ Eduflow

April 2019 - October 2020

As a full stack engineer I was delivering projects, contributing to product and UI/UX decisions. Worked on three projects: Peergrade, Eduflow and Notifly.

- Built a complex sidebar with drag and drop, contextual menus and course thumbnail editor.
- Main structure for editing activities front end architecture, settings and activity pages.
- Implemented fully responsive layout, optimizations for mobile devices and accessibility support.
- Account pages and authorization.

Tech stack: Python, Django, Graphene, PostgreSQL, Redis, GraphQL, Relay, React, TypeScript, CSS, Webpack, Heroku, Selenium.

### Software Engineer @ AzRy

August 2016 - February 2018

Worked on two main projects: Legislative Herald of Georgia, World Food Programme

- Developed **Drupal 7/8** module with heavy **DOM** manipulation using **VanillaJS** for documents parallel view where two unstructured, non-identical **HTML** documents should be scrolled simultaneously.
- Refactored application to make fully accessible and compliant to WCAG and WAI-ARIA standards.
- Voice synthesizer, which enables users to listen to highlighted texts in Georgian
- Integrated and maintained live support chat system.
- Implemented document management system.

Tech stack: PHP, Drupal 7, Drupal 8, JavaScript.

### Software Engineer @ Origin Eight

March 2017 - Jul 2017

Developed and maintained Drupal 8 modules and themes.

Tech stack: PHP, Drupal 8, JavaScript, CSS.

#### Software Engineer @ Geocell

August 2014 - Jan 2016

Developed several applications for other employees:

- Built an app with **NodeJS** and **Express** framework with the main goal to retrieve data from several different databases such as **MongoDB** and **MySQL**, on the front-end I was using Bootstrap and **jQuery**. Application helped customer service to easily access user data, increased productivity.
- Chrome extension with built in calculator which adds key bindings to an existing system and is used company wide by customer support and tech team. Calculator takes arguments from highlighted text in **DOM** and the key bindings helped the team to substantially increase productivity and reduce response time to incidents.
- Python script that enables the tech team to easily copy files and folders from one server to another.

Tech stack: Python, NodeJS, Express, JavaScript, MongoDB, Mysql.

### Software Engineer @ Omedia

December 2013 - July 2014

- Developed responsive web sites on with custom modules and themes for Drupal 7 with integration to third party applications.
- Built fully responsive frontend architecture for SPA using VanillaJS in addition worked on advanced CSS animations.

Tech stack: PHP, Drupal 7, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Gulp.

#### Software Engineer @ ITDC

May 2013 - October 2013

- Built fully responsive front-end web sites with scalable CSS architecture Tech stack: jQuery, VanillaJS, Gulp, Grunt, Compass, Sass.

#### Community involvement

#### Co-founder & Co-Organizer @ uniHack

December 2013 - December 2015

- Organized 4 large international college hackatons in Tbilisi, Georgia

# **Education**

### Computer Science, B.S.

Fall 2014 - present

Caucasus University, Tbilisi, Georgia

I was one of the best student, with the highest GPA(3.75) score in the <u>School of Technology</u>, because I started full-time work after third year I haven't finished it yet.